<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>grundlage on elektrophon</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/tags/grundlage/</link><description>Recent content in grundlage on elektrophon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.elektrophon.org/tags/grundlage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>cmos_filter</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/cmos_filter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/cmos_filter/</guid><description>about A state variable filter is constructed with two integrator amplifier and a summer. The integrators are low bass filters. The output of both is mixed back to the input. This will give three resonses. A High pass, band pass and low pass response.
2021-12-07T11:09:28.862331 image/svg+xml Matplotlib v3.5.0, https://matplotlib.org/ *{stroke-linejoin: round; stroke-linecap: butt} 2021-12-07T11:09:28.</description></item><item><title>cmos</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/cmos_buffer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/cmos_buffer/</guid><description>The basic usage and pin mapping is explained in the datasheet [1]. It is not very common to use this chip for linear amplification, especially in our days where opamps are very cheap to get. But there is also an application note [2] that explains the basic usage. It will not go into too many details, we will have to figure out some details on our own.
2021-12-07T11:09:21.</description></item><item><title>licht</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/licht/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/licht/</guid><description>enlighten the front panels uses a lot of energy and cause glitches on the power rail. never the less an eluminated panel looks much better and the different types of connectors can be marked with different colors.
color type [V] red audio signal +-5 green cv signal +-5 yellow cv pulse or gate +10 white cv pulse or gate +10 the chip should be powered by +5V/GND.</description></item><item><title>ringmodulation</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/ringmodulator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/ringmodulator/</guid><description>amplitude modulation In amplitude modulation the amplitude (signal strength) of the carrier changes in proportion to the message signal.
$$ \begin{array}{c} c(t) = A \sin(2 \pi f_c t)\, \end{array} $$Where A is the amplitude of the carrier singal and the function of f the modulation signal. Amplitude Modulation is a multiplication of the two signals.
2021-12-07T11:36:21.096290 image/svg+xml Matplotlib v3.5.0, https://matplotlib.org/ *{stroke-linejoin: round; stroke-linecap: butt} 2021-12-07T11:36:21.</description></item><item><title>vermarkung</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/vermarkung/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/vermarkung/</guid><description>pcb size The size of the modules is described in U (Rack Unit) and HP (Horizontal Pitch). U is the height of the module. One U is 1.75" = 44.45mm. The modules are 3U, the total height would be 3*44.45mm=133.4mm. This would be too large when rails with lips are used. Therefore the height of the modules is 128.5mm. The HP is or 1/5" (5.08 mm). The real sizes are slightly smaller because of the tolerance of the PCB production process.</description></item><item><title>arbeitsplatz</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/arbeitsplatz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/arbeitsplatz/</guid><description>essential software All the schematics and PCB are created in Kicad. The documentation is based on jupyter notebooks. The jupyter notebooks run simulations and create plots of the results. Also other
The software used to create the notebooks, schematics and PCB's.
KiCad EDA A Cross Platform and Open Source Electronics Design Automation Suite. Visual Studio Code free code editor from microsoft. jupyter notebooks can be executed and previewed in code.</description></item></channel></rss>