<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>module on elektrophon</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/categories/module/</link><description>Recent content in module on elektrophon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.elektrophon.org/categories/module/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>kontur</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/kontur/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/kontur/</guid><description>construction The AD/AR contains two envelope circuits and one pulse timer. Both will have a trigger at the end of the envelope or delayed pulse. The end of envelope is not connected to another input, those must be patched. The output of the delayed pulse is connected to the input of the first envelope.
2021-12-22T09:04:58.370842 image/svg+xml Matplotlib v3.5.1, https://matplotlib.org/ *{stroke-linejoin: round; stroke-linecap: butt} 2021-12-22T09:04:58.</description></item><item><title>welle</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/welle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/welle/</guid><description>construction There are various wavefolder circuits out there. the most famous is the serge wave multiplier middle section. Welle is implemented using the basic idea from Jürgen Haible [1] and the modifications from Yves Usson [2].
2021-12-22T09:23:01.523437 image/svg+xml Matplotlib v3.5.1, https://matplotlib.org/ *{stroke-linejoin: round; stroke-linecap: butt} 2021-12-22T09:23:01.</description></item><item><title>tiefpass</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/tiefpass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/tiefpass/</guid><description>construction The lowpass gate filter topology is a Sallen and Key filter where the two resistors are replaced with a vactrol. A vactrol is a device with an LDR and a LED. The brightness of the LED will change the resistance of the LDR. This gives a variable cutoff frequency. The lowest frequency has to be in the inaudible range. This will make the LPG quiet if there is no control voltage applied.</description></item><item><title>equalizer</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/equalizer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/equalizer/</guid><description>construction the function depends on the patching and settings of the potentiometers. an attenuverter is used in different modules like the Serge VCS, Maths and also in the polivoks filter. while this module can be used as a simple mixer you can also adjust cv signals. such a signal can be simply attenuated or inverted. when feeding in a positive singal slope (for example from an adsr). the signal will be turned to a neagative dc singal.</description></item><item><title>produkt</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/produkt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/produkt/</guid><description>construction for the final circuit input and output buffering and biasing is needed. the buffering is done with opamps.
2021-12-22T09:13:47.026771 image/svg+xml Matplotlib v3.5.1, https://matplotlib.org/ *{stroke-linejoin: round; stroke-linecap: butt} 2021-12-22T09:13:47.</description></item><item><title>steckfeld</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/steckfeld/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/steckfeld/</guid><description>construction I don't like working with breadboards. But sometimes you want to test things before you order a PCB. Connecting existing modules to the breadboard is especially tedious and building blocks like input mixer or output buffer occur in most circuits. This is where Steckfeld helps. It provides connectors for the patch cables and the necessary circuits for input and output. First, I made the resistors pluggable. But I never replaced them and finaly soldered them in.</description></item><item><title>summe</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/summe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/summe/</guid><description>Construction The function depends on the patching and settings of the potentiometers. When the potentiometer is at the centre position, the output signal is muted. No output signal is present. When turning to the right, the output will get louder until the output signal is equal to the input. When turning the potentiometer to the left, the output signal will be phase-shifted by 180°.
The first input is wired to a default DC voltage of +5V.</description></item><item><title>kraft</title><link>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/kraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.elektrophon.org/posts/kraft/</guid><description>construction The circuit is very simple. The 15AC input is half bridge rectified. The positive half is providing the +15V, the negative the -15V. The capacitors remove the ripple and the regulators provide a clean DC voltage. The 5V regulator circuit is taken directly from the datasheet. The 5V should not be used for audio circuits. It is meant to drive LED's and as input for regulators providing the power for a microchip.</description></item></channel></rss>